It was a welcome change when they put me on terrorism watch duty.
他们有一个可喜的变化  就是把我放在了监控恐怖分子的岗位值班
Every day I'd go in and I'd get starting points for SIGINT.
我每天的工作就是收集信情
which is Signals Intelligence.
也就是信号情报
A lot of them were American, which felt strange
有许多人都曾是美国人  很奇怪
but you just keep reminding yourself
但是你必须时刻提醒自己
I could stop a dirty bomb attack and save thousands of lives.
我能阻止脏弹袭击并拯救很多人
Thing is, you're not just following your bad guy targets, you're also following their metadata.
但是你不仅仅是追踪坏蛋  你还追踪了他们的元数据
Which is basically, all the phone numbers that they're in touch with.
也就是基本上  所有跟他们通过话的电话号码
Let's say your target is a shady Iranian banker operating out of Beirut.
比如说目标是一个在贝鲁特的黑心伊朗银行家
Okay, so, you're watching his stuff, but you're also watching all the people that he talks to.
好了  那么你追踪了他的数据  也就跟踪了所有跟他联系过的人
Including, you know, his cousin who's just some dentist living in Buffalo.
甚至包括他那在巴法络的牙医老表
And then you've gotta watch all of that guy's contacts.
然后你还得追踪这个人的联系名单
And by the time you go a third hop out from the original target, you're watching this bartender
当你的监控迭代三次之后  你竟然发现一个酒保
chat with her mother about Botox.
在跟他妈妈聊肉毒杆菌
'Cause three hops from anyone with, say, 40 contacts...
因为随便一个有40个联系人的人迭代三次
you're looking at a list of 2.5 million people.
你都是在监控250万人